John 20.
The first day of the week cometh Mary M
agdalene early, when it was yet dark, un
to the sepulchre, and seeth the stone ta
ken away from the sepulchre.
Then she runneth, and cometh to Simon P
eter, and to the other disciple, whom Je
sus loved, and saith unto them, They hav
e taken away the Lord out of the sepulch
re, and we know not where they have laid
him.
Peter therefore went forth, and that ot
her disciple, and came to the sepulchre.
So they ran both together: and the othe
r disciple did outrun Peter, and came fi
rst to the sepulchre.
And he stooping down, and looking in, s
aw the linen clothes lying; yet went he
not in.
Then cometh Simon Peter following him,
and went into the sepulchre, and seeth t
he linen clothes lie, And the napkin, th
at was about his head, not lying with th
e linen clothes, but wrapped together in
a place by itself.
Then went in also that other disciple,
which came first to the sepulchre, and h
e saw, and believed.
For as yet they knew not the scripture,
that he must rise again from the dead.
Then the disciples went away again unto
their own home.
But Mary stood without at the sepulchre
weeping: and as she wept, she stooped d
own, and looked into the sepulchre, And
seeth two angels in white sitting, the o
ne at the head, and the other at the fee
t, where the body of Jesus had lain.
And they say unto her, Woman, why weepe
st thou?
She saith unto them, Because they have
taken away my Lord, and I know not where
they have laid him.
And when she had thus said, she turned
herself back, and saw Jesus standing, an
d knew not that it was Jesus.
Jesus saith unto her, Woman, why weepes
t thou?
whom seekest thou?
She, supposing him to be the gardener,
saith unto him, Sir, if thou have borne
him hence, tell me where thou hast laid
him, and I will take him away.
Jesus saith unto her, Mary.
She turned herself, and saith unto him,
Rabboni; which is to say, Master.
Jesus saith unto her, Touch me not; for
I am not yet ascended to my Father: but
go to my brethren, and say unto them, I
ascend unto my Father, and your Father;
and to my God, and your God.
Mary Magdalene came and told the discip
les that she had seen the Lord, and that
he had spoken these things unto her.
Then the same day at evening, being the
first day of the week, when the doors w
ere shut where the disciples were assemb
led for fear of the Jews, came Jesus and
stood in the midst, and saith unto them
, Peace be unto you.
And when he had so said, he shewed unto
them his hands and his side.
Then were the disciples glad, when they
saw the Lord.
Then said Jesus to them again, Peace be
unto you: as my Father hath sent me, ev
en so send I you.
And when he had said this, he breathed
on them, and saith unto them, Receive ye
the Holy Ghost: Whose soever sins ye re
mit, they are remitted unto them; and wh
ose soever sins ye retain, they are reta
ined.
But Thomas, one of the twelve, called Di
dymus, was not with them when Jesus came
.
The other disciples therefore said unto
him, We have seen the Lord.
But he said unto them, Except I shall s
ee in his hands the print of the nails,
and put my finger into the print of the
nails, and thrust my hand into his side,
I will not believe.
And after eight days again his disciple
s were within, and Thomas with them: the
n came Jesus, the doors being shut, and
stood in the midst, and said, Peace be u
nto you.
Then saith he to Thomas, reach hither t
hy finger, and behold my hands; and reac
h hither thy hand, and thrust it into my
side: and be not faithless, but believi
ng.
And Thomas answered and said unto him,
My Lord and my God.
Jesus saith unto him, Thomas, because t
hou hast seen me, thou hast believed: bl
essed are they that have not seen, and y
et have believed.
And many other signs truly did Jesus in
the presence of his disciples, which are
not written in this book: But these are
written, that ye might believe that Jes
us is the Christ, the Son of God; and th
at believing ye might have life through
his name.